Stewart L. Udall papers, 1950-2010
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series V: Personal Files, 1950-1977
  - Honors and Awards: National Collegiate Athletic Association, Chicago,Convention-Silver Anniversary Award, Speech. January 12, 1973 (Box 201a, Folder 6)
  - Honors and Awards: Honorary Deputy Sheriff of Tarrant County, Texas. November 1973 (Box 201a, Folder 7)
  - Honors and Awards: New Hampshire College, Manchester- Honorary Degree. May 18, 1974 (Box 201a, Folder 8)
  - Honors and Awards: Knox College Commencement, Illinois-Honorary Degree. June 7, 1975 (Box 201a, Folder 9)
  - Honors and Awards: Wilmington College Commencement, Ohio-Honorary Degree. June 15, 1975 (Box 201a, Folder 10)
  - Honors and Awards: Oversize. (Box 202)
    Girl Scouts of the United States of America Plaque, 1962
    North Dakota State Water Commission Plaque, October 8, 1963
    National Association of Colored Women’s Clubs, Denver, Colorado-1964 "Citizen of the Year" Award, July 30, 1964. See also Box 195
    Suffolk County Science Teachers Association-Fire Island Award, October 1964. See also Boxes 195, 103, 131, 156
    Adelphi University Award-Garden City, Long Island Award, October 21, 1964. See also Box 195
    Los Angeles Junior Chamber of Commerce Wood Plaque, March 11, 1965. See also Box 196
    Mohave Pioneers Historical Society, Arizona-Certificate, April 27, 1968
    Mid-West Electric Consumers Association Award, October 31, 1968. See also Box 143, Folder 3
    Employees and Alumni Association of the National Park Service Certificate
  - Honors and Awards: Oversize. (Box 203)
    American Airlines, Commission as an Admiral of the Flagship Fleet, September 1, 1959
    League of Women Voters of the District of Columbia, Award of Merit, June 30, 1960
    Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, Commission on the Rank of Admiral of the Fleet, 1961
    Syracuse University, Honorary Degree, June 4, 1961. See also Box 194
    Downtown-Lower Manhattan Association, Citation, October 10, 1961. See also Box 194
    Kentucky, Bert Combs, Governor,Commission as a Kentucky Colonel, March 19, 1963
    American Veterans Committee Award, June 1, 1963. See also Box 195
    Dickinson College, Carlisle, Pennsylvania. Honorary Degree, June 2, 1963. See also Box 195
    Raw Materials Managers of Major Steel Companies of Japan, Citation in appreciation of Stweart Udall's efforts to encourage trade in coking coal, November 22, 1963
    Discover America Program Award, 1964
    Winchester (in Behalf of the Nation’s Outdoor Writers), Outdoorsman of the Year, 1964
    March Tuna Research Foundation, Citation, 1964
    Izaak Walton League of America. Award, June 25, 1964. See also Box 195
    Long Island Executive Breakfast Club, and Long Island Visitors Bureau Citation, Octover 21, 1964. See also Boxes 195, 103,131, 156, and 202
    Long Island Executive Breakfast Club, and Long Island Visitors Bureau. Citation.See also Boxes 195, 103,131, 156, and 202
    Garden Club of America Citation, 1965. See Box 197 for Medal
    Dartmouth College, New Hampshire, Honorary Degree, June 13, 1965. See also Box 196
    International Water Quality Exposition, Conservation Man of the Year, august 25, 1965
    Mayors and Municipal Assemblies of Various Localities in Puerto Rico, Citation, January 23, 1966
    Izaak Walton League of America, National Life Member, 1967
    National Society of Interior Designers, Thomas Jefferson Award, June 14, 1967
    Board of Supervisors, Orange County, California. Resolution, November 14, 1967. See also Box 137, Folder 13
    City of Huntington Beach, California and Huntington Beach Chamber of Commerce, Citation, November 1967. See also Box 137, Folder 13
    Wildlife Society, Aldo Leopold Award and Medal, March 12, 1968. See also Box 199
    Advisory Board on National Parks, Historic Sites, Building and Monuments, Citation, April 18, 1968
    Crow Tribe of Indians. Award, July 12, 1968. See also Box 142, Folder 14
    Sheriff of Tarrant County, Texas, Honorary Deputy Sheriff, November 1973
    New Hampshire College, Manchester, Honorary Degree-May 18, 1974
  - Stewart Udall Miscellaneous and Personal Material: Oversize, 7 Photographs of Stewart Udall and President Johnson. (Box 204, Folder 1)
  - Stewart Udall Miscellaneous and Personal Material: Oversize, 8 Political Cartoons. Some original, Some Iinscribed. 1954-1975 (Box 204, Folder 2)
  - Stewart Udall Miscellaneous and Personal Material: Miscellaneous. 1960-1975 (Box 204, Folder 3)
    Poster for the 1960 Political Campaign
    Photographs of Swearing-in of 85th Congress, January 1957 (3 of Stewart Udall, One with President Kennedy)
    Drawings (2) of Stewart Udall
    Drawing of the Justice Department Building. Inscribed to Stewart Udall by Robert F. Kennedy
    President John Fitzgerald Kennedy Memorial Stamp-special mounted and presented to Stewart Udall, May 29, 1964
    Color clippings from Seventeen, June 1964, Stewart Udall and college student; Mounted Clippings from the Washington Post, July 31, 1964; "Udall Scores 8 in Post;" "Stewart Udall Enhances Interior’s Mission," Gallup Daily Independent, Gallup New Mexico, December 21, 1964; "Washington in 1980?" by Benjamin Ruhe, Washington Star, February 27, 1966; "Inside Interior’s Udall: a long Affair with the Out-of-Doors," Arizona Republic Sunday Supplement, June 29, 1975; "Whether Pocatello or Pawtucket, You Can’t Go Home Again," Washington Post, June 29, 1975 (story about ex-Congressmen and Cabinet members; Stewart Udall Featured)
  - Stewart Udall Miscellaneous and Personal Material: Oversize, 1954 Political Campaign Clippings, Posters, etc. 1954 (Box 204, Folder 4)
  - LP Records. (Box 205)
    CBS Radio Network: "The Leading Question," March 28, 1957
    CBS Radio Network: "The Leading Question," July 1959
    CBS Radio Network: "Capitol Cloakroom," November 1961
    NBC Radio-TV: "Meet the Press," July 4, 1965. See also Box 122
- Series VI: Publications, 1957-1977
  - Publications: Articles, "A Defense of the Seniority System"- New York Times Magazine. January 13, 1957 (Box 206, Folder 1)
  - Publications: Articles, "Eisenhower and Congress" - New Republic. June 3, 1957 (Box 206, Folder 2)
  - Publications: Articles, "A Congressman Defends the House" - New York Times Magazine. January 12, 1958 (Box 206, Folder 3-4)
  - Publications: Articles, "Why Adlai Stevenson Haunts the Democrats"- New Republic. Includes letter from Adlai Stevenson. May 19, 1958 (Box 206, Folder 5)
  - Publications: Articles, "Our Education Budget Also Needs Balancing - The Reporter. June 25, 1959 (Box 206, Folder 6)
  - Publications: Articles, Various. 1959-1961 (Box 206, Folder 7)
    "An Evening with Robert Frost," Arizona Daily Star, Tucson, June 5, 1959
    Untitled, Arizona Alumnus, University of Arizona, 1959 Holiday Issue
    "Try the Vigorous Life," The Week Magazine, February 12, 1961. See also Box 211
    "We Must Act Now for More National Park," Audubon Magazine, March/April 1961
    "Needed - An Integrated Conservation Credo," Arizona Sportsmen’s News, May 1961
    "Landscape Unlimited Adorn Parks," Christian Science Monitor, May 12, 1961
    "Enjoy Your Play Areas - But Protect Them," Family Weekly, May 21, 1961. See Box 211
    "Interdependence-Key to Mutual Welfare of Canada and the United States," INCO, Spring 1961
    "Simple Joys of Roughing It" McCall’s, June 1961
    "National Parks for the Future" Atlantic Monthly, June 1961
    "Power for the National Security and Growth," Public Utilities Fortnightly, June 8, 1961
    "A Matter of Life or Death in Africa" National Parks Magazine, September 1961
    "A Precious Heritage to Protect for the Ages " Allied Industrial Worker, September 1961. See Box 211
    "Keeping Pennsylvania Green " Reprinted in the Philadelphia Evening Bulletin, October 5, 1961 from the Pennsylvania "Internal Affairs" Monthly Bulletin.
    "Young Man, Be a Politician," Esquire, December 1961
  - Publications: Articles, "Frost’s ‘Unique Gift Outright," New York Times Magazine. See also Box 211. March 26, 1961 (Box 206, Folder 8)
  - Publications: Articles, "Plea for...A Green Legacy," Christian Science Monitor. September 11, 1961 (Box 206, Folder 9)
  - Publications: Articles, North American Newspaper Alliance Series on American Indians. September 24-26, 1961 (Box 206, Folder 10)
  - Publications: Articles: "We Need ‘Distance in Our Eyes’" Life Magazine. December 22, 1961 (Box 206, Folder 11)
  - Publications: Articles: Various: 1962 (Box 207, Folder 1)
    "Land Anniversaries in 1962 are Farm Anniversaries, Too!" American Livestock Journal, January 1962
    "Monumental Look at Washington," New York Times Magazine, April 1, 1962. See also Box 211
    "Open Space - the Threat and the Opportunity," The Rotarian, May 1962
    "Our Efforts to Preserve Our Outdoor Heritage," Denver Post (Empire Magazine) May 6, 1962
    "To Save the Wonder of the Wilderness," New York Times Magazine, May 27, 1962. See also Box 211
    "The Conservation Challenge of the 60’s," The Carpenter, June 1962
    "The Answer to America’s Power Supply Challenge," Public Utilities Fortnightly, June 7, 1962
    Title "Missing Guns and Hunting," November 1962
    "We Must Save Our Open Space," Trail and Timberline, 1962.
  - Publications: Articles, Various. 1963 (Box 207, Folder 2)
    "Washington - Its Parks and Open Spaces," AIA Journal, January 1963
    "A Citizens’ Lobby for the Outdoors" Park Maintenance, February 1963
    "Can Federal Architecture Be Creative?" Arizona Architect, February 1963
    "Save the Redwoods," New York Herald Tribune, May 25, 1963
    "A Population Explosion is Not Inevitable," Izaak Walton Magazine, July 1963
    "Power Engineering in the USSR," Mechanical Engineering, August 1963
    "To Save Wildlife and Aid Us Too," New York Times Magazine, September 15, 1963. See also Box 211
    Science Series: North American Newspaper Alliance, 1963
    "What the Big Outdoor Boss Has In Mind," Life Magazine? 1963? See Box 211
  - Publications: Articles: Various. 1964 (Box 207, Folder 3)
    "America Deserves Untouched Beauty of Wilderness Areas," ARGUS, Seattle Washington, January 10, 1964
    "The Arts as a National Resource," Saturday Review, March 28, 1964
    "We Must Save the Beauty of Our Land," The Carpenter, April 1964
    "Cities in Trouble," (Chapter 12 of The Quiet Crisis) AIA Journal, April 1964. See Box 213 The Quiet Crisis - Reprints.
    "The Conservation Challenge," Izaak Walton Magazine, April 1964
    "Give Our Landscape Parity With Payrolls " The Daily Pantagraph, April 17, 1964
    "EHV Sets the Pace," Public Utilities Fortnightly, June 4, 1964
    "Parks: The Challenge of Excellence," Trends in Parks & Recreation, July 1964
    "Wild Rivers," Fishing Tackle Trade News, September 1964
    "Once Lost, Never Recaptured," New York Times Magazine, September 13, 1964. See Box 211 Publications
    "Udall Tells How to Save Central ‘Museum’" Washington Post, September 12, 1964
    "Wild Rivers " Pageant, October 1964
    "Is Our Country Running Out of Water?" Coronet, October 1964
    "His Anger is Fully Justified," Sports Illustrated, November 16, 1964. Stewart Udall’s answer to article by Robert H. Boyle, "America Down the Drain," in same issue.
    "A Message for Biologists," Bioscience, November 1964. Reprinted in Virginia Wildlife, February, 1965
  - Publications: Articles, 1962-1971: "The Legacy of Rachel Carson," Saturday Review. May 16, 1964 (Box 207, Folder 4)
  - Publications: Articles, Various. 1965-1968 (Box 207, Folder 5)
    "Stream and Air Quality Crisis," Pulp & Paper, March 15, 1965
    "Duty to the Future," (editorial) Saturday Review, May 22, 1965
    "Now Look Here, Voyager," Life Magazine, June 18, 1965
    "The Scandal of Our National Parks," This Week Magazine, August 1, 1965. See Box 212 Publications
    "Our Vanishing Elbow Room," Seattle Post-Intelligencer: Northwest Today. September 12, 1965. See Box 212 Publications
    "Ending the Water Crisis," Saturday Review, October 23, 1965
    "Population vs. Resources in ‘The Great Chain of Life’," Catalyst, Fall, 1965
    "An Invitation to County Outdoor Action - R.S.V.P." American County Government, April 1966
    "America, the More Beautiful," Everyweek, April 20, 1966
    "Grand Canyon’s Highest and Best Use" (editorial) Sierra Club Bulletin, May 1966
    "The New Urban Conservation," Nation’s Cities, June 1966
    "It’s Family Camping Time," UAW Solidarity, July 1966. See Box 212 Publications
    "Hope for Earth’s Fragile Wildlife," Christian Science Monitor, September 19, 1966. See Box 212 Publications
    "Public Policy and Pest Control, "Reprinted from Scientific Aspects of Pest Control. Publication #1402, National Academy of Sciences, National Research Council, 1966
    "The Face of Tomorrow," Los Angeles Times (West Magazine) June 11, 1967
    "Help Save Our Heritage," Modern Photography, October 1967
    "Call Them Human Life Refugees," Audubon Magazine, January/February 1968
    Article on the Navajo Indians-title page only, This Week Magazine, June 9, 1968
  - Publications: Articles: "Our Perilous Population Implosion," Saturday Review. September 2, 1967 (Box 207, Folder 6-8)
  - Publications: Articles, Various. 1969-1971 (Box 207, Folder 9)
    "The Earth Is Still Our Home," This Week Magazine, April 6, 1969. See also Box 212 Publications
    "Conservation’s New Look in the USA," ORYX, May 1969
    "A Capitol on the Desert," Arizona Republic Sunday Supplement, October 5, 1969. See also Box 212 Publications
    "Stewart Udall Comments on the Future of the Sierra Club,"(editorial) California Tomorrow, 1969?
    "Rachel Carson," McGraw-Hill Encyclopedia of World Biography, 1970?
    "A Few Prejudices, " (contributed to a travel article entitled "Where to Go - In a Wicked World ") New York Times, May 17, 1970
    "Seven Things You Can Do to Make America Beautiful" House and Garden, June 1970
    "After Earth Day, What?" Newsday, June 18, 1970. See Box 212 Publications
    "Turned On by Windmills," New York Times, February 13, 1971. Correspondence regarding Revisions in the "Nature Monuments Book" with the County Beautiful Corporation, 1971
  - Publications: Articles, "The Value Revolution," New York Times. June 7, 1969 (Box 207, Folder 11)
  - Publications: Articles: "Wheels Through the Wilderness," Venture: the Traveler’s World. June 1969 (Box 207, Folder 12)
  - Publications: Articles: "The Indians," The American Way. May 1971 (Box 207, Folder 13)
  - Publications: Articles, Various. 1972 (Box 208, Folder 1)
    "How to Save the National Parks: Ration People," New York Times, February 17, 1972
    "They Walk With Beauty in the Land of Dineh," National Wildlife, June/July 1972
    "Lame-Duck Cabinet," New York Times, December 28, 1972
    "1972: A Troubled Birthday Year for the National Parks," TV Guide, 1972
  - Publications: Articles: "What Shall Be Done at Stockholm?" Washington, DC, Star. June 4, 1972 (Box 208, Folder 2)
  - Publications: Articles, "‘...And Miles to Go Before I Sleep’- Robert Frost’s Last Adventure," New York Times Magazine. Includes Letters from Wallace Stegner, Herman Wouk, McGeorge Bundy, and Others. June 11, 1972 (Box 208, Folder 3-5)
  - Publications: Articles: "The Last Traffic Jam, " Atlantic Monthly. October 1972 (Box 208, Folder 6)
  - Publications: Articles, Various. 1973 (Box 208, Folder 7)
    Includes
    "The Energy Crunch is Urgent," New York Times, May 11, 1973. Published as a letter to the Editor
    "The ABC’s of Energy Reform," New York Times, July 12, 1973
    "Some Second Thoughts on Stockholm," American University Law Review, Summer 1973
    "The Energy Illusions," New York Times, November 21, 1973
    "Thoughts About the Kennedy Legacy," Los Angeles Times, November 22, 1973. Includes letters from Edward Kennedy, Mike Mansfield, and Arthur Goldberg
    "Energy ...We Must Heed the Cassandras," Washington, D.C. Star-News, December 2, 1973. See also Box 212 Publications
  - Publications: Articles, "The Energy Crisis: A Radical Solution," World Magazine. May 1973 (Box 208, Folder 8)
  - Publications: Articles, "The Politics of the Environment," Contributory Article to Encyclopedia of the Future. 1973 (Box 208, Folder 9)
  - Publications: Articles, Various. 1974 (Box 208, Folder 10)
    "How Families Can Fight Inflation,"September 1974 (Not Published?)
    "Sewage: Our Most Neglected Resource,." (editorial) Annals of Internal Medicine, December 1974. Co-author Jeff Stansbury
    "Which Way Out for Detroit?" New York Times, December 3. 1974. Published as a Letter to the Editor.
  - Publications: Articles, "End of an Era," Washington Post. January 13, 1974 (Box 208, Folder 11)
  - Publications: Articles, Various. 1977 (Box 208, Folder 12)
    "Supertechnology: Another God That Failed," New Mexico Alumnus, March 30, 1977
    "Putting the Spring Into Energy," New York Times, March 30. 1977
    "A Continent for Active Men," Mainliner (Magazine of the United Airlines) June 1977
    "The Failed American Dream," Washington Post, June 12, 1977
    "Our Technological Ego Trip is Ending," Denver Post, June 19, 1977
  - Publications: Miscellaneous. 1945-1946 (Box 209, Folder 1)
    "A Testament: Compiled on the Completion of a War" Typescript (carbon), August 1945
    "A Veteran’s Look at the ‘Right-to-Work’ Bill," Reprinted from the Apache County Independent News, St. Johns, Arizona, 1946?
  - Publications: Miscellaneous Articles Not Fully Identified or Dated. No Date (Box 209, Folder 2)
  - Publications: Letter to the Editor Regarding Mormons and the Negro, Dialogue. Summer 1967 (Box 209, Folder 3-6)
  - Publications: Book Reviews. No Date (Box 209, Folder 7)
  - Publications: Poetry. No Date (Box 209, Folder 8)
  - Publications: Introductions, Forewords, etc. No Date (Box 209, Folder 9)
  - Publications: Proposed Civil War Drama. No Date (Box 209, Folder 10)
  - Publications: Proposed Article- "Early Arizona Politics and Politicians." No Date (Box 209, Folder 11)
  - Publications: Proposed Article-"The Mormons and the Labor Problem." (Box 209, Folder 12)
  - Publications: Proposed Article-Publications: Proposed Article- Based on Stewart Udall’s 1962 Russian Trip. (Box 209, Folder 13)
  - Publications: Proposed Article-"Moderation is a Two-way Street." (Submitted to The Reporter, Not Published.) (Box 209, Folder 14)
  - Publications: Proposed Article-"Last Look at Glenn." (Box 209, Folder 15)
  - Publications: Newsday, Correspondence, etc. 1970-1972 (Box 210, Folder 1)
  - Publications: Newsday Column. June 1970-July 1972 (Box 210, Folder 2)
  - Publications: Oversize. (Album containing the following items which did not fit into Boxes 206 and 207. Some items relate to additional materials (correspondence, drafts, etc.) in the boxes indicated.) 1961-1964 (Box 211)
    "Try the Vigorous Life." This Week Magazine, February 12, 1961. See also Box 206, folder 7
    "Frost’s ‘Unique Gift Outright’." New York Times Magazine, March 26, 1961. See also Box 206, folder 8
    "Enjoy Your Play Areas - But Protect Them," Family Weekly, May 21, 1961
    "A Precious Heritage to Protect for the Ages," Allied Industrial Worker, September 1961
    "Monumental Look At Washington," New York Times Magazine, April 1, 1962.
    "Our Efforts to Preserve Our Outdoor Heritage," Denver Post, (Empire Magazine) May 6, 1962
    "To Save the Wonder of the Wilderness," New York Times Magazine, May 27, 1962. See also Box 207, folder 1
    "To Save Wildlife and Aid Us, Too," New York Times Magazine, September 15, 1963. See also Box 207, folder 2
    "What the Big Outdoor Boss Has In Mind," Life Magazine 1963?
    "Once Lost, Never Recaptured," New York Times Magazine, September 13, 1964
  - Publications: Oversize. (Album containing the following items which did fit into Boxes 207 and 208. Some items relate to additional materials in the boxes indicated.) 1965-1973 (Box 212)
    "The Scandal of Our National Parks," This Week Magazine, August 1, 1965
    "Our Vanishing Elbow Room," Seattle Post-Intelligence (Northwest Today) September 12, 1965
    "It’s Family Camping Time," UAW Solidarity, July 1966
    "Hope for Earth’s Fragile Wildlife," Christian Science Monitor, September 19, 1966
    Article on the Navajo Indians -Title page only, This Week Magazine, June 9, 1968
    "The Earth is Still Our Home," This Week Magazine, April 6, 1969. See also Box 207, folder 10
    "A Capitol On the Desert," Arizona Republic, Sunday Supplement, October 5, 1969. See also Box 207, folder 10
    "A Few Prejudices," (contributed to a travel article entitled "Where to Go -In a Wicked World ") New York Times, May 17, 1970. See also Box 207, folder 10
    "After Earth Day What?" Newsday, June 18, 1970.
    "How to Save the National Parks: Ration People," New York Times, February 17, 1972. See also Box 208, folder 1
    "Energy...We Must Heed the Cassandras," Washington Star-News, October 2, 1973. See also Box 208, folder 7
  - Publications: The Quiet Crisis- Correspondence with Publisher. 1963 (Box 213, Folder 1)
  - Publications: The Quiet Crisis-Correspondence, Miscellaneous. 1963 (Box 213, Folder 2)
  - Publications: The Quiet Crisis, Fan Mail. Includes letters from Joseph Wood Krutch, A. Dobrynin, Franklin D. Roosevelt, Jr., Brooks Atkinson, John Kenneth Galbraith, Howard K. Smith, Charles Collingwood, Paul Horgan, Herbert Humphrey, etc. 1963 (Box 213, Folder 3)
  - Publications: The Quiet Crisis, Awards. Includes National Association of Independent Schools Annual Book Award; Garden Club of New Jersey, Gold Medal; Pennsylvania Horticultural Society, Distinguished Achievement Award. 1964 (Box 213, Folder 4)
  - Publications: The Quiet Crisis, Reprints. 1963 (Box 213, Folder 5)
  - Publications: The Quiet Crisis, Outlines. 1963 (Box 213, Folder 6)
  - Publications: The Quiet Crisis, Foreword. 1963 (Box 213, Folder 7)
  - Publications: The Quiet Crisis, Introduction by President Kennedy. 1963 (Box 213, Folder 8)
  - Publications: The Quiet Crisis, Chapter 1-"The Land Wisdom of the Indians." 1963 (Box 213, Folder 9-10)
  - Publications: The Quiet Crisis, Chapter 2-"The Birth of a Land Policy: Thomas Jefferson." 1963 (Box 213, Folder 11-12)
  - Publications: The Quiet Crisis, 1963: Chapter 3: "The White Indians: Daniel Boone, Jed Smith," etc. 1963 (Box 214, Folder 1-2)
  - Publications: The Quiet Crisis, Chapter 4-"The Stir of Conscience: Thoreau and the Naturalist." 1963 (Box 214, Folder 3-4)
  - Publications: The Quiet Crisis, Chapter 5-"The Raid on Resources." 1963 (Box 214, Folder 5-6)
  - Publications: The Quiet Crisis, Chapter 6-"The Beginning of Wisdom: George Perkins Marsh." 1963 (Box 215, Folder 1-2)
  - Publications: The Quiet Crisis, Chapter 7-"The Beginning of Action: Carl Schurz and John Wesley Powell." 1963 (Box 215, Folder 3-4)
  - Publications: The Quiet Crisis, Chapter 8- "The Woodlands: Gifford Pinchot and the Foresters." 1963 (Box 215, Folder 5)
  - Publications: The Quiet Crisis, Chapter 9-"Wild and Park Lands: John Muir." 1963 (Box 215, Folder 6-7)
  - Publications: The Quiet Crisis, Chapter 10- "Men Must Act: The Roosevelt's and Politics." 1963 (Box 216, Folder 1-2)
  - Publications: The Quiet Crisis, Chapter 11-"Individual Action: Organizers and Philanthropists." 1963 (Box 216, Folder 3)
  - Publications: The Quiet Crisis, Chapter 12-"Cities in Trouble: Frederick Law Olmsted." 1963 (Box 216, Folder 4-6)
  - Publications: The Quiet Crisis, Chapter 13- "Conservation and the Future." 1963 (Box 216, Folder 7-8)
  - Publications: The Quiet Crisis, Chapter 14-"Notes on a Land Ethic for Tomorrow." 1963 (Box 216, Folder 9)
  - Publications: The Quiet Crisis, Final Manuscript-Chapters 1-14. 1963 (Box 217, Folder 1-4)
  - Publications: The Quiet Crisis, Printer’s Copy-Chapters 1-14. 1963 (Box 217, Folder 5-8)
  - Publications: The Quiet Crisis, Galley Proof. 1963 (Box 217, Folder 9)